What Chato's land doesn't kill, Chato will.
Chato's Land is a western film directed by Michael Winner.
In 1870s New Mexico, a half-breed kills a bigoted sheriff in self-defense but the
posse that eventually hunts him finds itself in dangerous territory.
Pardon Chato, played by Charles Bronson.
Quincey Whitmore, played by Jack Palance.
Joshua Everette, played by James Whitmore.
Jubal Hooker, played by Simon Oakland.
Elias Hooker, played by Ralph Waite.
Earl Hooker, played by Richard Jordan.
Chato's Land is a 1972 Western Technicolor film directed by Michael
Winner, starring Charles Bronson and Jack Palance.
In Apache country, the half-native Chato shoots the local sheriff in self-defense, and finds himself hunted by a
posse of ex-Confederates, who rape his wife and leave her hogtied in the open as a bait to trap him.
After freeing her, Chato uses his superior fieldcraft skills
to lure each of the posse to their deaths.
The film can be classified in the revisionist Western genre, which was at its height at the
time, with a dramatizing of racism and oblique referencing of the Vietnam War.
The original screenplay was written by Gerry Wilson.
The film explores themes of rape, self-defense, revenge, tracker, fugitive.